Benjamin Greene

Albuquerque · New Mexico · benjamin.k.greene@gmail.com 818.486.9409

I am a curious and enthusiastic developer. Tinkering, both physically and in code makes me tick, and I deeply enjoy applying machine learning approaches to problems of vastly different domains. I have 7+ years of work experience, 4 of which are technical.

RELEVANT SKILLS

Language

• Experience in Spanish and Russian

Programming

- Python, C, Java
- Scheme, Bash, LATEX, PostgreSQL
- Scrum, continuous integration
- Git, test-driven development

OTHER SKILLS

- Extensive physical, electronic, firmware, and software prototyping experience.
- Significant experience with Linux distributions
- Formal training in book preservation, repair, and archiving
- Formal training in typesetting, printing, and metalsmithing

LINKS

- LinkedIn: benjaminkgreene
- Git: alcofrisbas

Advisors

- Undergrad Advisor: Jeff Ondich jondich@carleton.edu
- Undergrad Capstone Advisor: Dave Musicant dmusicant@carleton.edu

EDUCATION

BA: COMPUTER SCIENCE

June 2019

Carleton College

Relevant Coursework: Software Design, Database Systems, Syntactic Theory, Linguistic Field Methods, Diachronic Linguistics, Graph Theory, Computer Graphics, Machine Learning, Computational Models of Learning, Natural Language Procesing, Database Systems

EXPERIENCE

SAIC | Machine Learning Engineer

OCT 2019-PRESENT

- Investigate and create cutting-edge machine learning algorithms
- Implement larger-than-memory data managing software for machine learning applications
- Collaborate with customers on domain-specific machine learning applications

SANDIA NATIONAL LAB | YEAR ROUND R&D INTERN 2018-SEP 2019

- Center For Cyber Defenders Member
- Developed and worked with data analysis toolkits in foreign language analysis
- Implemented fast forward deployed cyber analytics software and researched graph-related data-processing methods
- Researched machine learning techniques for synthesizing and analyzing network data

Datrium | Extern

Dec 2017

- Learned about scalable cloud data storage and open convergence server infrastructure
- Assisted in front-end web app bug fixing

REALITONE INC. | PROGRAMMER

2017-2018

- Designed software to process audio samples
- Created algorithms primarily in Python to seamlessly splice and loop sounds for use in a vocal synthesizer

INDEPENDENT BOOK REPAIR BUSINESS

2017-2019

- Worked with clients on personal library upkeep, including appraisals, repair, protective services, and referrals
- Provided instruction for clients that want to learn more about book preservation

Carleton College Library Preservation Assistant 2016-2019

- Conducted minor and major repair on library books to aid in circulation
- $\bullet\,$ Undertook preservation projects on several-hundred-year-old books and manuscripts
- Designed and created templates for improved book enclosures

Los Angeles Philharmonic, Togos, Hogan Brothers 2014-2019

- Interfaced with customers in various service industry positions
- Engaged in active customer-related problem-solving and unruly crowd management

AWARDS

Larson Fellowship for Photojournalism in Latin America

2017

- Explored the impact of European culture in modern day South America by interviewing and capturing portraits of individuals in Peru, Ecuador, and Colombia
- $\bullet\,$ Designed photo essay and exhibition in Carleton College Athenaeum